Contact

281-671-4283 (Mobile) dora.loun@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dora-loun (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Critical Care Nursing Conscious Sedation Critical Thinking

Certifications

NIH Stroke Scale Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Registered Nurse
Basic Life Support - Provider

Dora Loun, RN

Travel Nurse at LiquidAgents Healthcare

Houston, Texas

Summary

Highly skilled Registered Nurse (RN) with more than seven years of experience providing superior care while ensuring quality patient care and regulatory compliance. Recognized as an exceptional team leader and problem solver who is organized, resourceful, and compassionate. Passionate patient advocate and effective communicator.

Experience

LiquidAgents Healthcare Travel Nurse February 2020 - Present (6 months)

Kendall Regional Medical Center, Miami, FL
 ICU RN, Travel Contract, March 16, 2020 – April 25, 2020
 Level 1 Trauma Center, Teaching Facility, 50+ Bed ICU

Self-Employed

Independent Health Care and Wellness Consultant June 2004 - Present (16 years 2 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Health and Wellness Coaching; Disease Management Coaching; Sexual Health and Well-being Consulting; Comprehensive Patient Care Coordination; Case Management; Telephonic Triage; Symptom Management; Crisis Intervention; Interdisciplinary Collaboration and Coordination; Private Duty In-Home Pain Management; Private Duty In-Home Chronic Illness Management; Private Duty In-Home Pediatric Psychiatric Illness Management; Private Duty In-Home Pediatric Developmental Delay Management

Kindred Healthcare
Critical Care Registered Nurse/House Supervisor
April 2019 - March 2020 (1 year)
Tomball, Texas

Oversee multiple hospital departments in the absence of management.

Responsible for addressing patient care, staffing, physician needs, scheduling procedures, admission, transfer, and discharge management, and any issues that may arise.

Supervise nurses and ancillary staff members.

Provide aggressive, specialized nursing care to the chronic, critically ill and/ or medically complex adult patient who requires extended recovery times according to the Texas Nurse Practice Act and hospital policy Deliver quality patient care by contributing to the nursing care plan from admission to discharge.

Prepare assessment of patient's progress and keep family informed.

Monitor pain management procedures.

Participate in the discharge planning process.

Ensure current and accurate patient documentation.

Supervise nurses and ancillary staff members.

Triumph Healthcare - North Clinical Liaison August 2009 - December 2009 (5 months)

Houston, Texas

Pre-screen referred patients for appropriateness of transfer to LTACH setting. Establish and maintain relationships with referral sources including doctors, social workers, case managers, and home health agencies as well as provide education on admission criteria and referral process. Attend professional association meetings and design and conduct presentations to established and potential referral sources.

Memorial Hermann Sw Hospital ICU Staff RN September 2008 - August 2009 (1 year)

Houston, Texas Area

Nursing Process Application to Patients with Varied and Complex Needs; Comprehensive Patient Care Planning; Coordination, and Implementation Across the Continuum of Care; Focused and Comprehensive Subjective and Objective Assessment; IV Therapy; Medication Administration, and Reconciliation; Accurate and Timely Documentation of Care; Conscious Sedation; ICP Measurement, Monitoring, and Intervention As Necessary; Basic and Advanced Life Support; Wound Care; ADL Assistance; Case Management; ET Tube and Tracheostomy Care; Procedure Assistance; Drain Tube Management; Catheter Insertion and Care; Telemetry Initiation,

Monitoring, Interpretation, and Intervention As Necessary; Post-Surgical Care; Adverse Event Prevention; NG and Feeding Tube Insertion and Management; Interdisciplinary Team Coordination and Collaboration; Patient Care Evaluation and Modification as Necessary; Physician's Orders Implementation; Patient Safety, Comfort, and Privacy Assurance; Aseptic and Sterile Techniques Utilization as Appropriate; Discharge Planning; Symptom Management; Crisis Intervention and Management; Data Input, Retrieval, and Interpretation; Patient and Caregiver Education

Coastal Staff Relief Home Health Registered Nurse May 2008 - September 2008 (5 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Nursing Process Application to Patients with Varied and Complex Needs; Comprehensive Patient Care Planning; Coordination, and Implementation Across the Continuum of Care; Focused and Comprehensive Subjective and Objective Assessment; IV Therapy; Medication Administration, and Reconciliation; Accurate and Timely Documentation of Care; Basic and Advanced Life Support; Wound Care; ADL Assistance; Case Management; ET Tube and Tracheostomy Care; Telephonic and On-site Triage; Drain Tube Management; Post-Surgical Care; Adverse Event Prevention; Feeding Tube Management; Interdisciplinary Team Coordination and Collaboration; Patient Care Evaluation and Modification as Necessary; Physician's Orders Implementation; Patient Safety, Comfort, and Privacy Assurance; Aseptic and Sterile Techniques Utilization as Appropriate; Discharge Planning; Symptom Management; Patient and Caregiver Education; Health and Wellness Coaching; Crisis Intervention and Management; Ancillary Support Personnel Direction and Oversight; Quality Assurance; Talent Performance Evaluation; Coding; Material Tracking; Inventory Control; Data Input, Retrieval, and Interpretation

IPH Home Health Home Care
Home Health Registered Nurse
January 2007 - May 2008 (1 year 5 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Nursing Process Application to Patients with Varied and Complex Needs; Comprehensive Patient Care Planning; Coordination, and Implementation Across the Continuum of Care; Focused and Comprehensive Subjective and Objective Assessment; IV Therapy; Medication Administration, and Reconciliation; Accurate and Timely Documentation of Care; Basic Life

Support; Wound Care; ADL Assistance; Case Management; Telephonic and On-site Triage; Drain Tube Management; Post-Surgical Care; Adverse Event Prevention; Feeding Tube Management; Interdisciplinary Team Coordination and Collaboration; Patient Care Evaluation and Modification as Necessary; Physician's Orders Implementation; Patient Safety, Comfort, and Privacy Assurance; Aseptic and Sterile Techniques Utilization as Appropriate; Discharge Planning; Symptom Management; Patient and Caregiver Education; Health and Wellness Coaching; Crisis Intervention and Management; Ancillary Support Personnel Direction and Oversight; Talent Performance Evaluation; Coding; Material Tracking; Inventory Control; Data Input, Retrieval, and Interpretation

Angleton Danbury Medical Center
ICU Staff Nurse/ICU Charge Nurse
June 2004 - January 2007 (2 years 8 months)

Nursing Process Application to Patients with Varied and Complex Needs; Comprehensive Patient Care Planning; Coordination, and Implementation Across the Continuum of Care; Focused and Comprehensive Subjective and Objective Assessment; IV Therapy; Medication Administration, and Reconciliation; Accurate and Timely Documentation of Care; Conscious Sedation; Basic and Advanced Life Support; Wound Care; ADL Assistance; Case Management; ET Tube and Tracheostomy Care; Procedure Assistance; Drain Tube Management; Catheter Insertion and Care; Telemetry Initiation, Monitoring, Interpretation, and Intervention As Necessary; Post-Surgical Care; Adverse Event Prevention; NG and Feeding Tube Insertion and Management; Interdisciplinary Team Coordination and Collaboration; Patient Care Evaluation and Modification as Necessary; Physician's Orders Implementation; Patient Safety, Comfort, and Privacy Assurance; Aseptic and Sterile Techniques Utilization as Appropriate; Discharge Planning; Symptom Management; Crisis Intervention and Management; Data Input, Retrieval, and Interpretation; Patient and Caregiver Education; Nursing and Ancillary Support Personnel Direction and Oversight; Patient Assignment; Team Leadership

Education

Western Governors University
RN - BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2019 - 2020)

Professional Healthcare Education Service, Inc.

Nurse Refresher Program, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2018 - 2018)

Galveston College

Associate Degree of Applied Science, Nursing · (2002 - 2004)